I always have.
ずっと好きでした
From the first time I saw you, I think.
きっと始めてあった時から
It took me a while to understand myself,
私は 分からなかった
but I fell in love too.
でも
好きに なってた
I guess it was just a dream...
ようするに あれか
夢オチか
You already said that yesterday.
それ昨日も言ってた
Ichika.
先輩
いくら夏だからって
I know it's summer, but you'll still catch a cold if you fall asleep out here.
こんなところで寝てたら風邪引いちゃうわ
So...
だから
Now I feel better.
これで安心
夢 見てたんです
I had this dream...
About what?
どんな
I dreamed that we got together.
先輩と恋人同士になる夢
現実だよ
That wasn't a dream.
なんか まだ信じられなくて
I still can't believe it.
We have Tanigawa to thank.
谷川さんのおかげ
She helped me realize how I felt.
私の気持ち 気づかせてくれたから
谷川 まだ 体調悪いのかな
I wonder if she's still feeling under the weather..
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，请登录www.kamigami.org
日听：秋水无痕 翻译：yaya 校对：小草爱吃梨 Syura 时间轴：小青
This sucks. My eyes are still puffy.
ひどい まだ腫れてる
こんな顔じゃ 皆の前に出ていけない
I can't let everyone see me like this.
Don't worry about it. It's no worse than usu—
気にすることねえだろう
たいして変わんっ
Anyway, did you tell everyone?
それより 皆には連絡してくれたの
とりあえず 夏風邪ってことにしておいた
I told them you have a cold.
Well, that's good at least.
まあ 妥当よね
Thanks.
ありがとう
Hey, what are friends for?
ま 幼馴染だからな
ね 一昨日のことは
About the day before yesterday...
誰にも言ってねえから 安心しろよ
I haven't told anyone, so don't worry about it.
Hey, I'm making lunch now!
ねえ そろそろお昼にするけど
Do you want some, Tetsuro?
哲郎君 食べていく
I'd be glad t—
ああ ありがとうございま
Tetsuro has something to do! He's going home soon!
哲郎 用事あるって すぐ帰るから
そうみたいです
I guess so.
I love Kaito...
海人君が好き
I love him!
好きなの
Kanna,
柑菜
I...
俺
えっ おい
Hey!
帰る
I'm going home.
はちょっ
Wait!
Leave me alone.
ついてくんな
I'm sure...
今頃
right now...
あいつ
きっと
she's...
北原さん だよね
Kitahara, was it?
同じ小学校だったのに
We went to elementary school together, but this is the first time we've been in the same class.
一緒のクラスになるのは初めてだね
谷川柑菜 これからよろしく
I'm Tanigawa Kanna. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
うん よろしく
We're in the same class again?
また 同じクラスか
代わり映えしねえな
I just can't get rid of you, can I?
You took the words right out of my mouth.
それはこっちのセリフです
Oh. This is Ishigaki Tetsuro.
あ 石垣哲郎
We grew up together.
幼馴染
よろしく 北原美桜さん
Nice to meet you, Kitahara Mio.
How do you know my name?
私の 名前
You know each other?
あれ 知り合い
No, I just memorized all the girls' names and faces.
いや 女子の顔と名前を全部記憶してきた
I don't know whether to be impressed or think you're an idiot.
まめっていうか バカっていうか
Can't you just see I'm a gentleman who champions the cause of feminism?
フェミニストのジェントルマンって解釈はできない
Nope.
できない
時間 かかったんだぜ
Memorizing them was so much effort.
無駄な努力
Effort wasted.
It's been...
あれから もう 三年
three years already.
Hey!
Tetsuro...
哲郎君
Where are you headed?
どっか行くの
柑菜のお見舞いに
I want to see how Kanna is doing.
ああ やめたほうがいい
You probably shouldn't.
いや 今あいつ目
Her eyes are— Cold...
目が
Her eyes are cold?
I meant she has a cold. She doesn't want to spread it.
風邪移すと嫌だからって
She wouldn't let me see her either.
俺も 断られたんだ
You went there?
柑菜のとこ 行ったんだ
She's my friend, after all.
幼馴染だからな
お 美桜
Mio?
お腹 空いてない
Are you hungry?
お見舞いのケーキ 無駄になっちゃうのなんだし
I made her a cake, and I'd hate to see it go to waste.
Thanks for that.
ごちそうさまでした
You're welcome.
はい お粗末さまです
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
What's that?
何
はあ フィルムの整理しようと思って
I thought I'd get all my reels in order.
檸檬先輩が山ほど撮ってきてくれるから
Lemon shot a mile of footage,
だいぶ 溜まって
so it's been piling up.
What is it?
なんですか
Do I need a reason?
何かないとダメ？
そんなこと
Not really...
You know,
私ね くっついてるのが好きみたい
I think I like cuddling.
Do you not like me like this?
海人君はこういうの嫌
No...
す そんなこと
I think I like it too.
俺も 嫌いじゃないんです
良かった
Good.
Don't mind me.
私のことは気にしないで
Keep going.
そのまま続けて
I mind.
気にします
So you two are a couple now, huh?
できたのね あなたたち
ま まあ
I guess.
Have you—
もう や
ああああ 何言い出すんですか
What are you implying?!
ドサクサに紛れて
Congratulations, Ichika.
良かったわね イチカ
ありがとう
Thank you.
Kirishima. I've got a gift for you.
霧島君 これは私からの プレゼントよ
What?
な 何
What is what?
何がです
だって今
She just gave you...
Lemon!
檸檬先輩
大切にするのよ
Treasure this miraculous joining of two souls well.
この 奇跡のような出会いを
ごちそうさん
Thanks!
I'm stuffed.
ああ 食った 食った
やっぱ 美桜のケーキはうまいわ
Your cake was delicious, Mio.
There's nothing good about me otherwise.
私には これぐらいしか 取り柄がないから
あるだけ いいじゃん
Better than nothing at all.
哲郎君だってあるよ
You have things going for you too.
背が高くて
You're tall, you're handsome, you're good with your hands,
ルックスがよくて
手先が器用で
and you're good at remembering the faces and names of girls.
女の子の顔と名前を覚えるのが得意で
I dunno about that last one.
そんなの取り柄じゃないって
I've wanted to ask you something for a while now.
聞きにくいこと
聞いていいかな
What is it?
何
Why did you ask Takatsuki to be in the movie?
映画作りにどうして 貴月先輩を誘ったの
Because it seemed like that's what Kai wanted.
海が そうしてほしそうだったからだよ
まさか 先輩が引き受けるとは思わなかったけど
I never thought she'd actually say yes.
柑菜の気持ち
You knew about Kanna's feelings, didn't you?
知ってたよね
Huh?
You've always been so close.
あんなに近くにいるんだもん
私が分かったんだから
If I noticed, I'm sure you did too.
知らないわけないよね
Why did you ask Takatsuki?
どうして 貴月先輩を誘ったの
先輩と霧島君が仲良くなったら
Did you want her and Kirishima to...
That's not it.
違う
Then Kanna would...
柑菜は
I said that's not it.
違うって
I just wanted to support Kai, so I asked her.
海を応援しようと思ったから 先輩に声をかけた
柑菜が映画作りに参加すれば
I thought the movie would bring Kai and Kanna together.
海人との距離が縮められると思った
それが どういう結果になるかなんて分かんねえけど
I didn't know it would turn out like this.
I just wanted to help both of them out.
俺はどっちも応援しようとしたんだ
That's all.
それだけだよ
So what about your own feelings?
だったら 哲郎君の気持ちはどこに行くの
What about your feelings for Kanna?
柑菜への気持ちは どこへ行くの
Huh? Come on...
なんだよそれ お前 何言って
What are you talking about?
I know because I've been watching you this whole time.
ずっと見てきたから 分かるよ
You've only had eyes for Kanna.
哲郎君はずっと柑菜のことだけ見てたから
That's not true.
そうなんじゃねえよ
俺は
I...
Why are you lying to yourself?
どうして 自分にウソをつくの
Nothing's going to resolve itself if you keep avoiding the problem.
そうやって はぐらかし続けても
時間が解決してくれるわけじゃないよ
You're the one who told me to just say what I want to say.
言いたいこと言えよって
私にそう言ったの哲郎君でしょう
That's why I tried to be brave for once.
だから 私は勇気を振り絞ったのに
I like you.
好き
Tetsuro,
哲郎君が 好き
I like you.
I love you.
大好き
あの時は返事はいいって言ったけど
I told you I didn't need an answer back then,
聞かせてくれる
but will you tell me now?
Mio... I...
美桜 俺は
お前のこと その
I don't dislike you.
嫌いじゃない
でも 俺 今は
But right now, I...
I understand.
分かった
I'm going home.
帰るね
I'll just act like nothing's wrong.
普通でいるんだ 私
夏休み 楽しく皆で映画を撮るの
We're all gonna have fun filming the movie over summer break.
We'll make the movie and show it at the school fair.
映画を作って 学園祭なんかで発表して
And I'll just continue being the usual Tanigawa Kanna.
とにかく いつもの谷川柑菜でいるの
That's my decision.
そう決めたの
柑菜な
Kanna...
谷川
Tanigawa? She was here toda—
谷川なら 今日 うちに
She loves you, Kai.
あいつ 海が好きだぜ
I love Kaito...
海人君が好き
I love him!
海人君が
What am I supposed to do?
どうしようってんだよ
What can I do?!
何が できるんだよ
Yours and Ours
Episode Ten
いてえ
That hurt...
Ichika!
先輩
何
Yeah?
Would you like to go take a walk to cool off a bit?
良かったら 湯冷ましがったら 散歩にでもいきません
Sounds good.
うん いいけど
Oh, I know.
そうね せっかくだから
Rinon!
りのん
Amazing!
おう すげえ
Isn't it?
でしょう
夜も素敵だろうなって
I figured the view would be great at night.
And it's such an important place for us.
その 思い出の場所だし
こんなにも自然が残ってる
It's so unspoiled by civilization.
It's weird.
おかしいな 初めて来た星なのに
It's my first time coming to this planet,
but it's like I can remember seeing all of this.
なんだか 懐かしい感じがする
Um, Ichika...
あのう 先輩
Will you let me help you look around?
改めて 俺にも
その 場所探し 手伝わせてもらえませんか
I want to help...
俺 少しでも 先輩の
Kaito...
海人君
Thank you.
ありがとう
Um...
あの
But don't worry.
でも もういいの
Sure, that's why I originally came to this planet,
確かに 私は それが目的でこの星に来たわ
but it was really just an excuse to start traveling.
というより この旅をきっかけにしたかったの
I didn't really have a reason.
別に 何があったわけじゃないの
だから 何かしたいと思って
I just thought I wanted to do something.
俺もです
Same with me.
俺も これで何かを始めたいと思ったんです
I wanted to start something using this.
I thought, "If I could create something..."
何か出来ればって
I see.
そっか
同じだったんですね
I guess we're the same.
That makes me want to help grant your wish even more.
なら 余計俺は先輩の願いを叶えてあげたい
Right now, I want to be with you.
今 私は海人君といたいの
I want to make a movie with you and the others.
海人君と 皆と 一緒に映画を撮りたい
That's my wish now.
それが 今の私の願いなの
いいかな
Is that all right?
I already knew...
分かっていたんだ
この世界に永遠は存在しないって
Nothing in this world lasts forever.
Can you not tell him because you're an alien?
宇宙人だから ダメって言うんですか
いつまでも一緒にいられないから
And you can't be with him because you can't stay here forever?
海人君の気持ちに答えられないっていうんですか
Are you going to use that as an excuse to keep running away from him?
そういうの言い訳にして
海人君から ずっと逃げ続ける気ですか
あれで良かったんだ
I did the right thing.
海人君の思いが叶うんだから
Kaito will be happy.
それで いいんだ
It's for the best.
Hey, what's going on?
ちょっと何なのよ
You haven't said anything since you got back.
帰ってきてから ずっと黙りでさ
Did something happen?
なんかあったの
You can tell your sister.
姉ちゃんに相談してみ
You know, that's your problem.
言っとくけど あんたの悪い部分はそこよ
Nothing's going to fix itself if you keep quiet.
黙ってたって物事は解決しないのよね
格好つけても無駄
You can't just keep acting cool.
You might look like you've got things under control,
そつなく生きてるように見えても
あたしから見りゃただのガキだっての
but I know you're just a kid at heart.
You're here because you left your husband. You have no room to talk.
出戻りが偉そうに人生語ってんじゃねえよ
I didn't leave him. I just ran away for a while.
出戻りじゃなくて 家出
Basically, I still have a home.
つまり 帰る場所があるってこと
A fight between wife and husband can take many forms.
夫婦喧嘩の種類にもいろいろあんのよ
But you haven't even gone out with a girl, so I don't think you'd understand.
ま 女の子と付き合ったこともないあんたには
分からないだろうけど
Man, it reeks of virgin in here.
ああ いやだいやだ
ここ 童貞の匂いがするわ
だったら かえ
Then get the hell—
来た来た
Oh, he's here.
Thanks for the room, Tetsuro.
世話になったね 哲郎
Anyway, good luck.
ま 頑張んな
You're late!
もう 遅い
まちくたびれた
I had to wait so long!
また このオチかの
And so she just leaves again?
はい もしもし
Hello?
Tetsuro?
哲郎
What's up, Kai?
どうした 海
I want to start filming again the day after tomorrow.
明後日から 撮影再開しようと思って
That okay with you?
いいか
Fine with me, but...
いいけど でも
Kirishima Kaito
Calling
Ichika will be there too.
先輩も ちゃんと来てくれるからさ
あ そうか
I see...
So did you two...
お前 もしかして先輩と
ああ それは 皆と会ったときにちゃんと話すよ
Oh, I'll tell everyone in person.
So you really...
じゃあ やっぱり
Pretty much.
うん まあ
Then...
じゃ 柑菜はどうするんだよ
what about Kanna?!
Kirishima Kaito
Calling
だから なおさら ちゃんと言わなくちゃ
That's why I need to talk to everyone and tell them
how I feel.
俺の気持ちを
Tetsuro, I...
哲郎 俺は
哲郎
Tetsuro?
What am I doing?
何やってんだ 俺は
Filming on Okinawa
うん よし
Okay. I'll be fine for tomorrow's shoot.
これなら 明日からの撮影も大丈夫
I'll be fine.
大丈夫 うん
大丈夫
Call for you, Kanna!
柑菜 電話
Filming on Okinawa
I'll be right there.
はい
Why did you call me out here?
何よ こんなところに呼び出して
I'm supposed to be getting over a cold.
一応病み上がりってことになってるんだから
Who cares? You're not all swollen up anymore.
いいじゃんか 腫れも収まってるし
I guess.
まあ ね
Aw yeah!
よっしゃ マジック
Magic!
Dang it, you got me.
ああ やられた
We came here a lot when we were in kindergarten.
幼稚園のごろ よく来たよな
Yeah.
そうだね
I was taller than you back then.
あのごろ 私のほうが背が高かったのにな
Now look how much taller you are.
いつの間にか こんなに差を付けられてさ
And you always saved me from getting bullied.
いじめられてた 俺を よく助けてくれてたよな
柑菜パンチは無敵だったもん
Beware the fearsome Kanna Punch.
You were pretty cool.
格好良かったよ
Why are you acting so creepy?
何よ 気味悪い
You didn't just call me out here to talk about the past, did you?
で 昔話するために 呼び出したわけじゃないんでしょう
Hey, what happened to your foot?
っていうか 何その足
Just a little accident.
ちょ ちょっとな
So what did you want?
で 要件は何なの
I, uh...
うん その
If you want to say something about Kaito, don't bother.
海人君のことなら 言わなくていいよ
I already know.
何となくわかるから
I'll be fine.
私は 大丈夫だから
If you don't need anything else, I'm going home.
他に用がないなら 帰るね
I thought everything would be fine if things worked out between you and Kai!
お前と海がうまく行けばいいと思ってた
でも そんなの見たくなかった
But I didn't want to see that happen!
I thought that if Kai and Ichika hit it off, you'd be open to whatever.
海と先輩がうまく行けば
お前がフリーになるとか
But that would never happen.
つまんねえ期待してさ
It was stupid of me to think it would.
そんなこと あるわけねえのに
Tetsuro?
哲郎
I played with the heart of the girl I like, only to make her cry.
好きな女の子 振り回して挙句泣かせて
And now I can't do anything about it!
何もできねえで
The girl you like?
好きな人って
う ウソでしょう
You're kidding, right?
I'm serious.
本気
いつから
Since when?
For a long time now.
ずっと前から
もう 頭ん中 くしゃくしゃになってるときに
My mind's already a mess,
and now you drop this on me too? You jerk!
いきなり何言い出すのよ バカ
I know the timing's really bad,
ホント タイミング悪いよな
but I'm glad to finally get it off my chest.
けど ようやく言えた
哲郎
Tetsuro...
I know.
分かってる お前は 海のことが好きだよな
You really like Kai, don't you?
Kai likes Ichika, but that doesn't change anything, does it?
海がイチカ先輩を好きでも
そうだよな
And that's what I liked about you.
そういうお前が好きだった
Why do you get to say all that stuff and look so happy?
何よ
自分だけ言いたいこと言って
満足したような顔して
When I...
私は
I...
我慢すんな 柑菜は柑菜のままでいいんだ
Don't try to hold it all in.
You should just be yourself.
お 女の子の髪を軽々しく触るな
Don't touch a girl's hair like that!
I already know that!
言われなくても分かってる
Thanks!
ありがとう
You can cry, you know.
泣いていいよ
Not gonna happen.
泣かねえよ
You're so stubborn.
意地っ張り
Shut up.
うるさい
Actually, should you even be here to see this?
っていうかさ お前ここに来るのは犯則だよ
Girls are tenacious.
女の子は強かなんです
You're strong.
お前 強いよ
You can do a lot when you're in love.
好きな人ができるよ 強くなれるんだよ
I was able to change because of you.
私は 哲郎君のお陰で変われたよ
No, I can at least think about changing, about being stronger, because of you.
ううん 少なくとも 変わろうって
強くなろうって
思えるようになった
Thank you.
だから ありがとう
I should be thanking you.
こっちのセルフだって
I'll... do it...
私は
私の
Kaito!
海人君
谷川
Tanigawa...
Is your cold better?
もう 風邪いいのか
You want some watermelon?
西瓜 食う
海人君
Kaito...
Kaito, I like you!
私
海人君が好き
I've liked you for a long time now!
ずっと前から 好きだった
I love you!
大好き
I'm really sorry, Tanigawa...
ごめん 谷川
I love Ichika.
俺は 先輩が好きだ
I know.
知ってる
聞いてくれて ありがとう
Thanks for hearing me out.
Let's make the best movie ever!
映画 頑張ろうね
Yeah.
Even if nothing in this world lasts forever...
たとえ この世界に永遠がないとしても
それでも
we'll still...
僕らは
カメラオッケー
The camera's ready.
こっちもいいぞ
We're ready here.
I'm ready too!
準備できました
Scene #275. Ready... Action!
シーン２７５ よーい
はい
I'm sorry, Black Man,
ごめんなさい ブラックマン
but I want to stay on this planet!
でも 私はまだ この星にいたいの
この星には 大切なものがあるから
There are a lot of things I care about here,
so I'll...
だから
I looked for the reason why I fell in love
and tried solemn words
Once I realized my feelings,
the threads had gotten hopelessly tangled up
If I'd been able to say it
without hesitation
you wouldn't have to cry now
We paint a picture of feelings that pierce the clouds
Forever we will remember the scent of summer on the wind
My memories of when I was with someone
put color into my life, drop by drop, like the evening rain
Lemon said we'd be filming until later this evening.
今日は夕方まで みっちり撮影って 檸檬先輩言ってましたよ
I wonder how much longer all the filming will take.
あと どのぐらいで撮り終えるのかな
I think we'll still finish by the end of summer break.
夏休中には終わると思いますけど
Another week, huh?
あと一週間か
Ichika!
イチカ
You're alive, Ichika!
生きていたのね イチカ もう
Do you know how worried I was about you?!
どれだけ心配したと思ってるのよ
Sis...
お姉ちゃん
Ichika!
イチカ
Her... sister?
お姉 さん
Please don't go...
Episode Eleven
Why did you come to Earth?
お姉ちゃんどうして地球に
I bet she came to give us her blessing.
あれですよ きっと僕達を祝福しに来てくれたんですよ
Oh, come on! It's too early for that!
やだもん お姉ちゃんったら 気が早い
Or is she?
果たしてそうかしら